Mss.Ms.Coll.72
American Philosophical Society
Gratz Family Papers
1750-1974
Mss.Ms.Coll.72
American Philosophical Society
10.5 Linear feet
A collection of business and personal papers of three generations of the prominent Philadelphia Jewish family from 1750-1974. Business records include trade and land transactions (some in Yiddish) of the Gratz brothers, Barnard and Michael (1750-1804) with the business continued by Michael's sons: Simon, Hyman, Joseph, Jacob, and Benjamin (1791-1861). Personal correspondence are primarily letters to Rebecca Gratz from her sisters Rachel and Sarah (1795-1867) with later correspondence to Rachel's children: Horace and Sara Moses (1832-1879). Contains a small group of French letters related to Napoleon III, collected by family member Miriam Fox, and some heirloom artifacts.
Gratz family
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Sara McColl and Henry Joseph, 1992.
Biographical/Historical note
The Gratz family were important figures in the social, intellectual, and business life of Philadelphia during the Revolutionary and early national period, and were central figures in the Jewish community. Barnard (1738-1801) and Michael Gratz (1740-1811), emigrants from Silesia to Philadelphia, were business partners with extensive interests in coastal shipping and western trade, and actively supported America's independence. Michael's daughter, Rebecca (1781-1869), became arguably the most famous member of the family through her philanthropic activities, helping to found the Philadelphia Orphan Society (1815), the Hebrew Sunday School Society (1838), and supporting many other causes.
Bibliography
Ashton, Dianne. Rebecca Gratz: Women and Judaism in Antebellum America (Detroit: Wayne State University Press, 1997) Call no. B G77a
Rosenbloom, Joseph R. A Biographical Dictionary of Early American Jews: Colonial Times through 1800. ([Lexington]: University of Kentucky Press, 1960) Call no. 922.96 R72b
Scope and Contents note
A small collection of business and personal correspondence that reflects the life and times of a Jewish family living in Philadelphia during the late 18th and early 19th centuries. The letters present the business, cultural and private lives of three generations of Gratz family members. Organized by recipient, the bulk of the papers range from 1750, with the start of the family trade business in colonial America, to 1879, and the new social, religious and cultural institutions founded by the family in the new nation.
The papers (20 boxes; 10.5 linear feet) are divided into seven series:
Series I. Barnard and Michael Gratz 1750-1804 2 lin. ft.
Series II. Simon, Hyman, Joseph, Jacob, Benjamin Gratz 1791-1861 1.5 lin. ft.
Series III. Rebecca Gratz 1795-1867 2.5 lin. ft.
Series IV. Rachel Gratz Moses 1797-1879 0.5 lin. ft.
Series V. Sarah Gratz 1800-1808 4 folders
Series VI. Miscellaneous 1786-1974 2.5 lin. ft.
Series VII. Artifacts 1805-1900 0.5 lin. ft.
One Oversize flat box--files from all 7 Series 1 lin. ft.
Astor, John Jacob, 1763-1848; Bonaparte, Joseph, 1768-1844; Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836; Clay, Henry, 1777-1852; Croghan, George, d. 1782; Etting, Frances Gratz, 1771-1852; Eugénie, Empress, consort of Napoleon III, Emperor of the French, 1826-1920; Fenno, Maria; Franks, David; Gratz, Barnard, 1738-1801; Gratz, Benjamin, 1792-1884; Gratz, Hyman, 1776-1857; Gratz, Jacob, 1789-1856; Gratz, Joseph, 1785-1858; Gratz, Michael, 1740-1811; Gratz, Miriam Simon, 1749-1808; Gratz, Rebecca, 1781-1869; Gratz, Sarah, 1779-1817; Gratz, Simon, 1773-1839; Hays, Richea Gratz, 1774-1858; Irving, Washington, 1783-1859; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845; Joseph, Sarah Gratz Moses; Kemble, Fanny, 1809-1893; Moses, Horace, 1820-1893; Moses, Isaac, 1742-1818; Moses, Rachel Gratz, 1783-1823; Moses, Solomon, 1774-1857; Napoleon III, Emperor of the French, 1808-1873; Nathan, Rebecca Gratz Moses, 1810-1891; Rodman, Harriet Fenno, 1782-1808; Simon, Joseph, 1785-1858; Simon, Joseph, ca. 1712-1804; American Revolution; Art; Business and Skilled Trades; Business Records and Accounts; Colonial Politics; Congregation Mikveh Israel (Philadelphia, Pa.); Correspondence.; Early National Politics; Family Correspondence; Female Hebrew Benevolent Society (Philadelphia, Pa.); General Correspondence; Hebrew Sunday School Society of Philadelphia (Pa.); International Trade.; Land and Speculation; Land speculation; Legal Records; Literature; Literature, Arts, and Culture; Marriage and Family Life; Official Government Documents and Records; Orphan Society of Philadelphia (Pa.); Pennsylvania History; Philanthropy; Political Correspondence; Religion; Sketchbooks; Social Life and Custom; Surveying and Maps; Trade; Travel; Travel Narratives and Journals; Women's History
- Series I. Barnard and Michael Gratz, 1750-1804; The Gratz brothers were among the most prominent traders in colonial, revolutionary and republic Philadelphia. This series reflects much of their business and its changing nature, moving from a merchant firm to one speculating in Pennsylvania and western lands. The business transactions include Indian trade, especially around Fort Pitt and Illinois country. With some correspondence in Yiddish, areas covered include land sold in Mifflin and Lancaster County, economic conditions, legal entanglements, and the establishment of a Jewish congregation in Philadelphia. Also includes land surveys, trade lists and accounts, with a small series of letters to Mrs. Michael Gratz (Miriam Simon) primarily from her children.
  Biographical/Historical note
  In 1768, Barnard Gratz (1738-1801) and Michael Gratz (1740-1811), brothers born in Langendorf, Upper Silesia, Germany, became business partners in a company called B. & M. Gratz in Philadelphia. They were business associates of their cousins Solomon Henry and Jacob Henry in London. The brothers acted as purchasing and sales agents for Joseph Simon (ca. 1712-1804) in Lancaster, Pennsylvania and entered partnerships with George Croghan (d.1782) and William Trent (1715-1787) in land speculation and fur and Indian trading in central Pennsylvania. Both signed the Philadelphia Non-importation Resolutions adopted on October 2, 1765 and took the oath of allegiance to the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania and to the United States as a free nation, on November 7, 1777.
  Barnard Gratz married Richea Myers-Cohen in 1760. They had two children: Rachel (1764-1831), who married Solomon Etting of Baltimore, and Fanny who died with her mother in child birth. He did not remarry.
  Michael Gratz married Miriam Simon (1749-1808), a daughter of Joseph Simon. The couple had twelve children, ten of whom lived to adulthood. They include: Solomon (1770-1774), Frances (1771-1852) married Reuban Etting (1762-1848), Simon (1773-1839) married Mary Smith, Richea (1774-1858) married Samuel Hays (1764-1839), Hyman (1776-1857), Sarah (1779-1817), Rebecca (1781-1869), Rachel (1783-1823) married Solomon Moses (1774-1857), Joseph (1785-1858), Jonathan (died young), Jacob (1789-1856), and Benjamin (1792-1884) married Maria Cecil Gist in 1819, and Anna M. Boswell Shelby in 1843.
  The brothers helped establish the Congregation of Philadelphia Jews, which in 1782 became the Congregation Mikveh Israel.
  - Business Records, 1750-1804
    - Abraham, Alexander, 1776-1777
      Scope and Contents note
      Exchange of goods and services.
    - Act, 1797 March 10
      An act to afford relief to Washington Academy in the county of Washington.
    - Address book, 1756
      Names with account information.
    - Anderson, G., 1784 April 18
    - Anderson, M., 1779 November 6
      Purchase of leather.
    - Bank of Pennsylvania, 1780
      Excerpt on the establishment of the Bank of Pennsylvania, taken from Hazard's Register of Pennsylvania, vol. 2, p.259. Copied by Horace Moses, September 17, 1848.
    - Barr, Robert, 1785-1792
      Lexington tract.
    - Beall, Isaac and Company, 1779 June 3
    - Bodley, Thomas, 1801-1803
      Receipts of payments for land to Michael, Simon, Hyman Gratz and Joseph Simon.
    - Chancery suit, 1784-1786
    - Clara, Benjamin M., Undated
    - Clark, Alexander Abrahams, 1776
    - Clark, John, 1774-1792
    - Cohen, Solomon Myers, 1779-1789
    - Craig, John, 1784
    - Croghan, George, 1762-1784
    - Dabnee, Cornelius, 1779 June 18
    - Deeds, 1774-1793
    - DuVal, William, 1794-1796
    - Elizer, Isaac, 1768-1771
      Account.
    - Elliot, James, 1772 August 10
    - Etting, Rachel, 1792, 1796
      Barnard's daughter.
    - Etting, Simon, 1789 October 11
    - Etting, Solomon, 1784-1797
      Barnard's son-in-law.
    - Franks, David, 1750-1785
      Account of Franks and Company.
    - Franks, Moses, 1770-1789
    - Frazier, Hugh, 1794
      Land agreement with Elisha Graham.
    - Gibson, John, 1777
    - Goodwin, Thomas, 1794
    - Gratz, Barnard to Michael Gratz, 1766-1770
    - Gratz, Barnard to Michael Gratz, 1771-1775
    - Gratz, Barnard to Michael Gratz, 1776-1779
    - Gratz, Barnard to Michael Gratz, 1780-1784
    - Gratz, Barnard to Michael Gratz, 1785-1795
    - ______ to Barnard Gratz, 1760-1794, undated
    - ______ to Barnard and Michael Gratz, Undated
    - Gratz, Michael to Barnard Gratz, 1763-1776
    - Gratz, Michael to Barnard Gratz, 1777-1789
    - Gratz, Michael to Barnard Gratz, 1791-1794
    - ______ to Michael Gratz, 1768-1793, undated
    - Gratz, Rachel, 1790 December 18
    - Gratz, Simon, 1795-1796
    - Guillian, Robert, 1787 July 16
    - Harris, James, 1762
    - Hays, Christopher, 1786, 1792
    - Hays, Moses M., 1768-1791
    - Hendricks, James, 1779 September 9
    - Henry, Solomon, 1758, 1766-1789, undated
    - Hourton, James, 1789 February 18
    - Illinois and Wabash, 1773, 1779
      Regarding the lands of the United Companies of the Illinois and Wabash, Native American nations.
    - Illinois country, 1773
      Subscriptions for land purchased from Native Americans.
    - Jacobs, Jesse, 1766
    - Jewish Congregation of Philadelphia, 1782
    - Josephson, Manuel, 1761-1770
    - Judaeorum Statu, Undated
    - Land agreements, 1769-1796, undated
    - Land sold, 1788
    - Land surveys, 1774-1805, undated
    - Lawrence, John, 1789-1795
    - Leikas, Benjamin, 1795 February 15
    - Leipare, Garshom, 1773-1774
    - Levy, Aaron, 1781-1795
    - Levy, Abraham and Ezekiel, 1776 June 18
      Contract for Ezekiel to teach Hebrew to children for the Jewish Society.
    - Levy, Andrew, 1766-1793
    - Levy, E., 1791 November 27
    - Levy, Mordecai, 1786 October 1
    - Levy, Simon, 1780 December 20
    - Lists, 1767-1796, undated
      Accounts of customers.
    - Map, Undated
      Property of Joseph Wharton and Governor Franklin.
    - Marks, Henry, 1780, 1786
    - Mary and Fanny (Sloop), 1776-1778
    - Maund, John James, 1793 December 13
    - Mifflin County, 1792-1794
    - Mikveh Israel Synagogue, 1784 March 14
    - Miscellaneous, 1759-1799, undated
    - Morgan, George, 1768
    - Morton, William, 1792, 1794
    - Moses, Isaac, 1778-1795
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also, Series VI. Miscellaneous--Papers.
    - Murphy, Edward, 1769 February 9
    - Murray, William, 1773-1787
    - Myers, Israel, 1779 September 28
    - Myers, John, 1786 June 18
    - Myers, Joseph, 1779, 1781
    - Myers, Myer, 1766 November 23
    - Myers, Moses and Samuel, 1783-1785
    - Myers, Solomon, 1776-1786
    - N. Low Bard and Company, 1795
    - Nailen, Ralph, 1776 January 22
    - Nilson, George, 1794 July 17
    - Notes on judgements, 1786-1795
    - Philadelphia merchants, Undated
      Financial contributors to the American Revolution.
    - Phillips, Levy, 1784 November 20
    - Randolph, Edmond, 1785
    - Receipts, 1750-1784
    - Receipts, 1785-1804, undated
    - Rice, Patrick, 1779, 1786
    - Ronald, Andrew, 1786-1792
    - Ryan, Derry, 1795-1796
    - Sampson, ______, 1766 February 20
    - Samuel, Hyman to Aaron Alexander, 1791
    - Schenk, Abraham, 1772 August 4
    - Schuyler, _____, 1792 November 12
    - Shipping, 1770-1791
    - Simon, Joseph, 1766-1776
      Michael's father-in-law.
    - Simon, Joseph, 1777-1794, undated
    - Simpson, Edward, 1780-1781
    - Smith, Daniel, 1795 March 22
    - Smith, Johnston, 1779 May 16
    - Solomon, Joseph, Undated
    - Spear, Joseph, 1765, 1772
    - Steel, D., 1787 August 17
    - Trent, William, 1776, 1789
    - Unidentified, 1763-1791, undated
    - Waln, Nicholas, 1787
    - Washington, Bushard, 1791 November 16
    - Webb, Thomas and Company, 1779
    - Westfall, Abel, 1781-1793
    - Wulf, Isaac, Undated
  - Miriam Simon Gratz, 1771-1808
    - Etting, Frances Gratz, 1789-1802, undated
      Daughter.
    - Etting, Rachel, 1792 January 8
    - Etting, Reuben, 1800 January 28
      Son-in-law.
    - Gratz, Barnard, 1797 June 5
      Brother-in-law.
    - Gratz, Michael, 1771-1779, 1793
      Husband.
    - Gratz, Rachel and Solomon Etting, 1795 February 8
    - Gratz, Rachel, Undated
      Niece.
    - Gratz, Rebecca, 1797-1808, undated
    - Gratz, Rebecca, Rachel, Sarah, Undated
      Daughters.
    - Gratz, Rebecca, Rachel, Sarah, and Solomon Moses, 1806 June 25
    - Gratz, Rebecca and Sarah, 1798 July 20
    - Gratz, Sarah, 1800 December 18
    - Gratz, Simon, 1795-1796
      Son.
    - Joseph, Rebecca G., Undated
      Granddaughter.
    - Moses, Rachel Gratz, 1804-1806, undated
    - Schuyler, Shinah, 1789, 1796-1799, undated
      Sister.
    - Simon, Rose, Shinah Schuyler, Hyman Gratz, Undated
- Series II. Simon, Hyman, Joseph, Jacob, Benjamin Gratz, 1791-1861; Both personal and business papers of Michael Gratz five sons. Simon and Hyman Gratz inherited their father's and uncle's business, of which, some aspect, eventually, included all of the brothers. Dated from 1781-1861, most are related to land, business and legal affairs, with land surveys. Of note, letters from Joseph to Simon on a merchant trade trip to Europe in 1810, a series of letters from Simon to Benjamin in 1827, and executor documents pertaining to their father's estate.
  Simon Gratz (1773-1839) a merchant, with his business partner and brother Hyman, took over their father's and uncle's business, B & M Gratz, in 1798. The firm continued trading with the Indians and speculating lands westward, particularly along the Ohio River and in Kentucky. With lands inherited from Aaron Levy, Simon laid out the town of Gratz, Pennsylvania in 1805. He speculated in coal-rich land in Bear Gap in 1825. An active philanthropist, he was one of the founders of the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, a director of the Pennsylvania Botanical Garden, and a trustee of Congregation Mikveh Israel. Married to Mary Smith, they had eight children, four lived to adulthood.
  Hyman Gratz (1776-1857), merchant and philanthropist, started his business career in 1798 as a partner with his brother Simon in the family firm. He later turned his attention to the insurance business and banking. Also with his brother Simon, he was one of founders of the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts. He was the manager of the Jewish Publication Society and treasurer (1824-1856) of the Congregation Mikveh Israel in Philadelphia. His deed of trust in 1856, later established a Hebrew teaching school which became Gratz College. He remained unmarried.
  Joseph Gratz (1785-1858) and his brother Jacob Gratz (1789-1856) continued the management of the family business of land speculating, coastal shipping, and dry good supplies as their older brothers, Simon and Hyman, took to other business ventures. Each brother also served on the board of directors of the Philadelphia Institution for the Instruction of the Deaf and Dumb. Joseph and his sister Rebecca were particular friends of the author Washington Irving. These brothers remained unmarried.
  Benjamin Gratz (1792-1884), the youngest of Michael and Miriam Gratz children, was one of the first Jewish settlers in Kentucky. A graduate of the University of Pennsylvania, his knowledge of the law helped protect his family's business interests. He was a close friend of Henry Clay into whose family his daughter Anna married. His first wife was Maria Cecil Gist. They had six children, three lived to adulthood. Benjamin's second wife was Anna Maria Boswell Shelby. They had three children, two lived to adulthood.
  - Papers, 1791-1860
    - Adriansen, John Jacob to Simon Gratz, 1810 July 16
    - Athenaeum of Philadelphia to Benjamin Gratz, 1819 February 1
    - Bank of the United States to Jacob Gratz, 1841 January 15
    - Bermerke, L. to Joseph Gratz, 1810 October 27
    - Biddle, George W. to Joseph Gratz Estate, 1860 June 25
    - Chancellor, Henry to Joseph Gratz, 1838 April 24
    - Clay, Henry to Hyman Gratz, 1833 July 27
    - Clay, Henry to Jacob Gratz, 1834 December 21
    - Cohen, Solomon to Joseph Gratz, 1851 April
    - Gratz, Benjamin to Jacob Gratz, 1827-1828
    - Gratz, Benjamin to ______, 1827 November 27
    - Gratz, Hyman to Laura H. Gratz, 1864 June 3
    - Gratz, Jacob to Joseph Gratz, 1810-1811
    - ______ to Jacob Gratz, 1848 March 2
    - Gratz, Joseph to Jacob Gratz, 1841
    - Gratz, Joseph and Horace Moses to Jacob Gratz, 1827 May 1
    - Gratz, Joseph to Simon Gratz, 1810 May-July
    - Gratz, Joseph to Simon Gratz, 1810 August-September
    - Gratz, Joseph to Simon Gratz, 1810 October- December
    - Gratz, Joseph to Simon Gratz, 1811-1812
    - Gratz, Joseph to Simon Gratz, Undated
    - Gratz, Joseph--Will, 1858 November 1
    - Gratz, Michael to Simon Gratz, 1791 September 1
    - Gratz, Rebecca to Joseph Gratz, 1806-1814
    - Gratz, Simon to Solomon Etting, 1810 January 15
    - Gratz, Simon to Benjamin Gratz, 1827 January-September
    - Gratz, Simon to Benjamin Gratz, 1827 October-November
      Benjamin Gratz to Jacob Gratz
    - Gratz, Simon to Jacob Gratz, 1840 July 29
    - Irving, Washington to Joseph Gratz, 1806, 1808
    - Lawrey, J.A. to Jacob Gratz, 1841 January 19
    - Leeser, Isaac to Jacob Gratz, 1830 May 13
    - Moses, Isaac and Sons to Simon Gratz, 1810 January 12
    - Murat, Caroline to Joseph Gratz, 1839 April 24
      Uncle.
    - Phillips, Lawrence and Sons to Joseph Gratz, 1840 December 3
    - Quay, Joseph F. to Jacob Gratz, 1848, 1849
    - Randle, J. to Henry Clay, 1841 February 22
      Regarding Jacob Gratz.
    - Stewart, Andrew to Joseph Gratz, 1839
    - Vaughan, Mr. to Mr. Gratz, 1838 January 12
    - Vinsent, James to Hyman Gratz, 1819 January 25
    - Wickliffe, Robert to Hyman Gratz, 1808 May 15
  - Business Records, 1796-1864
    - Abeel, James, Undated
    - Act, 1839 March 22
      To incorporate the Allegheny and Bald Eagle Railroad Coal and Iron Company.
    - Active (Ship), 1800-1810
    - Akerman, J.A., 1810
    - American Insurance Company, 1817-1818
    - Bank of South Carolina vs. Isaac Phillips and Joseph Moses, 1837 March
    - Baring Brothers, 1810-1811
    - Barr, Robert, 1818
      ... vs. the heirs of Michael Gratz, dec'd. Supreme Court of the United States, February term.
    - Brushear vs. Michael Gratz heirs, 1819 June 3
    - Chauncey, Charles and Horace Binney, 1827-1830
    - Checks, 1813-1856
    - Croghan Land Judgement, 1800-1816, 1828-1838
      Extracts of letters from Simon Gratz showing that he considered the judgement in Croghan and the lands purchased under it, as his own.
    - Deeds, 1810-1858
    - Dillingham, William, 1840
    - Edminston, Samuel, 1845
    - Fayette County, 1807-1814
    - Frye, Jacob, 1848 June 28
    - Gilliland, James, 1846
    - Goodwin, Thomas and Stevenson, 1816
    - Goodwin, Thomas and Stevenson, 1817
    - Goodwin, Thomas and Stevenson, 1818, undated
    - Gratz, Benjamin, 1819-1828
    - Gratz, Joseph, 1858, undated
      List of Doctors visits; appraisal of furnishings.
    - Gratz, Michael -- Estate, 1817-1845
    - Gratz, Sally, 1839
    - Gratz vs. Benner, 1825
    - Holmes, H., 1799 October 30
    - Huntingdon County, 1840 April 1
    - Land sold, 1808-1811, 1821-1830
    - Land sold, 1832-1859
    - Land surveys, 1803-1851, undated
    - Lexington tract, 1808-1814, undated
    - Lists, 1806-1855
    - Mifflin County, Pennsylvania, 1823
    - Miller vs. Gratz, 1838-1844
    - Miller vs. McKean, 1845
    - Miller vs. Samuels, 1847 December
    - Miscellaneous, 1810-1856
    - Mitchell, N.J., 1824, 1856-1857
    - Moore, Clark and Company, 1818
    - Morton, William, 1803-1806
    - Parish and Company, 1810 February-August
    - Parish and Company, 1810 September-December
    - Parish and Company, 1811 February-August, undated
    - Pendens, Lis, 1848
    - Pennsylvania Company for Insurance..., 1856 December 18
    - Petitions, 1837-1842
    - Phillips, Isaac and Samuel, 1844-1847
    - Purdue, Edward, 1822
    - Quay, J.T., 1844 October 19
    - Receipts, 1796-1864, undated
    - Receipts (in packets), 1818-1820
    - Rosalie (Ship), 1817-1818
    - Shipping permits, 1810
    - Spring Township, 1805, 1823
    - Steele, John, 1818
    - Stewart, Andrew, 1836, 1839
    - Teal, Peter and Harriet, 1857-1861
    - Thomas, William A., 1857 February 12
    - Wallis, Samuel, 1854
      Heirs of.
    - Wilkins, Charles, 1807-1813
- Series III. Rebecca Gratz, 1795-1867; Personal correspondence to Rebecca Gratz, seventh child of Michael and Miriam Gratz, from her sisters, in-laws, nieces, nephews, and friends from 1795-1867. Contains letters with descriptions of social activities of family members and their personal views on events of the day. The correspondents are primarily women, particularly her sisters Rachel and Sarah, her long-time friend Maria Fenno, and her nieces Rebecca G. Moses Nathan and Sara G. Moses Joseph.
  Rebecca Gratz (1781-1869), educator and philanthropist, was an advocate for the welfare and religious education of the young. Instrumental in the founding of the Philadelphia Orphan Society in 1815, she served as its secretary to the board of managers for forty years. She aided in the foundation of the Female Hebrew Benevolent Society in 1819, and in 1838, she instituted the Hebrew Sunday School, a model for Jewish education in America, serving as its president till 1864. A prolific letter writer, she was friendly with many literary figures, particularly Washington Irving. Though never married, she cared for her unmarried siblings and her sister, Rachel Gratz Moses, children.
  - Papers, 1795-1867
    - Aguilar, Grace, 1842 August 14
    - Allen, Lewis, 1841 October 11
    - Allen, Lewis, 1841 October
      Rebecca Gratz to...
    - Blair, F.P., 1841-1842
    - Bodley, Sara G., 1857 June 2
    - Boswell, Mary, 1844-1846
    - Boswell, Mary and Benjamin Gratz, 1844 April 30
    - Boswell, Mary and Sara G. Joseph, 1847 August 4
    - Boswell, Mary and Sara G. Moses, 1847 August 8
    - Brown, Mason, 1839 January 10
    - Caroline, Undated
      Cousin.
    - Chonteau, Julia, Undated
    - Cohen Children, 1857 September 23
    - Cohen, Elkalah, 1858
    - Cohen, Miriam G., 1838-1854
    - Cohen, Miriam G., 1855-1866
    - Cohen, Miriam G., 1857, 1862
    - Cohen, Sally M., 1797-1835, undated
    - Cohen, Sally M. and Sarah Gratz, 1808 May 15
    - Cohen, Solomon, 1834, 1851, 1861
    - Cohen, Solomon and Miriam G. Cohen, 1861 January 7
    - Crittenden, K., 1836 December 5
    - Eckard, R., Undated
    - Eckard, S.R., 1865 December 4
    - Edgeworth, Maria, 1839-1840
    - Edgeworth, Maria, Undated
    - Ellet, E.F., Undated
    - Ellet, E.F., Undated
    - Etting, Charles E., 1861 July 14
    - Etting, Ellen Hays, 1856?
    - Etting, Frances Gratz, 1799-1803, undated
    - Etting, Gratz, 1828 November 8
    - Etting, Josephine, 1856-1858, undated
    - Etting, Kitty, 1797 June
    - Etting, Miriam G., 1835 August 24
    - Etting, Rachel Gratz, 1809-1865, undated
    - Etting, Rachel and Richea Etting, 1809-1816, undated
    - Etting, Rachel and Solomon Etting, 1809
    - Etting, Richea, 1820-1822, undated
    - Etting, Sally, 1796 June 21
    - Etting, Shinah, Undated